Guide to the Herbert Matter Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 6: Master Photofile, linear 2.5 ft.
  - Subseries 6.02: Negatives
    - Nature; Southwest; Native Americans; New York City; Travel; Stanford; San Francisco; Portraits; Children; Indian musicians [5 of 7]., b/w 4"x5": 2 1/4": 2 1/4": half frame strips (Box 126, Folder 5)
      Negatives (labeled with numbers) 350-402.
    - Children; Animals; Industrial; Urban; Portraits; Sculpture; Beach; Family, Matter Studio, Calder framed 3D mixed media; Matter family, Calder Family, Jackson Pollock, Lee Krasner at beach [6 of 7]., b/w 4"x5": 2 1/4": 2 1/4": half frame strips (Box 126, Folder 6)
      Negatives (labeled with numbers) 403-706.
    - Family; Farm; Switzerland; Travel; Design Exhibition [7 of 7]., b/w 4"x5": 2 1/4": 2 1/4": half frame strips (Box 126, Folder 7)
      Negatives (labeled with numbers) 707-775.
- Series 7: 2 1/4 in. Negative Strips, 3 linear ft.
  This series contains uncut strips of black and white negatives, predominately 2 1/4" format. These are vintage negatives representing Matter's early commercial and non commercial work of the late 1930s through the late 1940s. Each strip has between ten to twelve individual images. Several of the negatives contained in this series were not printed, and in many instances the images are not otherwise represented in the collection.
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Singer Ranch[;] Gaspe[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 127, Folder 1)
    Gaspe (Quebec)
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Zebu[;] Alejadinho[;]Ouro Preto[;] Donkies[;] Figures on prison roof[;] Karen[;] Pundy[;] Donald[;] Pundy on the beach[;] Gregory's children[;] Artwork[;] Betty Hubbard[;] Dr. Hubbard[;] Sweeney[;] Pierre Matisse[;] Pedro[;] Baby Cohen[;] Mas Muffelt's Sunday school[;] Models fin Ladies H Journal[;] Brooks - Shroyer Ann[;] Pedro[;]., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 127, Folder 2)
    Ain, Gregory; Sweeney, James Johnson;Matisse, Pierre;; Ladies' Home Journal;; Ouro Preto, Brazil; Brazil
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Flying story Vogue[;] Miss Lakes[;] Mrs. Gross[;] Constellation[;] Ouro Preto[;] Sabara[;] Fouben araf Gaspe[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 127, Folder 3)
    Vogue;; Ouro Preto, Brazil; Sabarand#225; (Brazil); Gaspe (Quebec)
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Harper's Bazaar Cover July 1st 40[;] Mercedes Harper's Bazaar[;] Pundit[;] Vogue[;]" Includes one negative of Jackson Pollock in field. One negative of Esteban Vicente in field., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 128, Folder 1)
    Pollock, Jackson; Vicente, Esteban;; Harper's bazaar; Vogue
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Figure walking in street fin montage[;] Fashion magazine[;] Harper's gute fashion[;] Mrs. Leon[;] Ladies Home Journal[;] Puppen Jabrik fin montage[;] Harper's food for England[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 128, Folder 2)
    Harper's bazaar; Ladies' Home Journal
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Studio. construction for Fortune cover Ausichlen van[;] Studio in Beaux Art and Tudor City, Sebst portraits[;] Aufwalimen von Lewis in Gaspe[;] Geroinen/von Mercedes von studio[;] Swiss pavilion[;] Ily Shiller Kletten[;] New Bauhaus[;] Mergenthaler[;] Salem[;] Peguot Mills[;] Awkwiff[;] Queen Mary[;] Circus Madison Square Gardens[;] Circus in Freien kinder[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "NW Ayer and Son, inc.[;] Spectator for fashion show[;] Farnsworth[;] Schionen kopf fin looking thr wall Farnsworth[;] Licht diagram[;] Farnsworth[;] Schore kipple fin garden[;] Tourks[;] Planes[;] Saldin for container corporation[;] Boy's kopf fin General Electric[;] House and Garden[;] Spider web[;] Fighting French[;] Bonwit Teller[;] Kayser Nighgowns gloves[;] Negative from Warimen[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 129, Folder 1)
    Container Corporation of America; House and Garden; Bonwit Teller and Co., New York
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Bride's Magazine, Haiti and Cuba S.S. America[;] Sculptures Despian Brancusi, Metropolitan Museum[;] Harrison Versch[;] Gebande Bronx Zoo[;] World's Fair[;] Aalto and Aalto chairs[;] Teiressy Vallet Electricity[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 129, Folder 2)
    Brancusi, Constantin; Aalto, Alvar;; Bride's magazine; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.)
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Nov-Ad[;] Eringe[;] Saks[;] Tennis[;] Portraits Sert with mustache[;] Marian Oswald Sybille Schlon[;] Versuch Spainish Girl Duthwit[;] Architect Hythiuin[;] Gibbons[;] Cachewen and O ryendem[;] Kopf[;][;] Nino Martini[;] Cassandre[;] Percy Seitlin[;] Mc. Vitty[;] Leger[;] Madam Simon[;] Kocher Kind and House[;] Meric Callery and Tochler[;] Hitler repro.[;] Pedro[;] Beggy[;] Le Boutellier[;] Hans Hoffmann bein molen[;] Eigene Arbeiten photographiert[;] Saks[;] Glass pavilion[;] Holzmobiles[;] Schrawfenster[;] Reklanie in Mooememb[;] Swiss pavilion[;] Model[;] Harrison and Foulhoux[;] Civilian Defense poster (eagle)[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 129, Folder 3)
    Sert, Jose Luis; Oswald, Marion; Cassandre, A. M.; Seitlin, Percy; Leger, Fernand; Callery, Mary; Hofmann, Hans;; Saks Fifth Avenue
  - Rio; New York; George Washington Bridge (New York; N.Y.); Triborough Bridge (New York; N;Y;); Rockefeller Center; [4 of 6]., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 130, Folder 1)
    Rio; New York; George Washington Bridge (New York, N.Y.); Triborough Bridge (New York, N.Y.); Rockefeller Center
  - Canada Winter; Skiers; Includes strips of half frame negatives (skiers) [4 of 6]., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips. (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - Harper's bazaar; Calder; Alexander; [4 of 6]., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 130, Folder 3)
    Calder, Alexander;; Harper's bazaar
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Arthur Carles paintings[;] Infrared from Santa Fe[;] Boat trip to Rio and Boat pictures of Gaspe from montage[;] Mercedes Provincetown, few of Hans Hoffman[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 131, Folder 1)
    Bride's Magazine
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Around Charlie Eames in Venice[;] Gregory Ain[;] Lighting Drawing Dressing[;] Lucia[;] Lucia Pre Fab[;] Van Leyden[;] Mercedes[;] Tress[;] Karin hands[;] printing maching Reproductions[;] Japanese Flag and ship for GE Locomotives streamlined[;] Winter Swiss[;] Daner Russion[;] Airplans[;] Georgio de Chirico[;] Mouja[;] Curtis Aripogino[;] Turblent Waterfall[;] hans with Brille Ski and Ski onfrishinen Meuser[;] Acheit fin Pestalozzi Foundation[;] Plus[;] San Francisco Bridge[;] Golf and Polo spieler[;] Alfe Souvine[;]", b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 131, Folder 2)
    Mondrian, Piet; Carles, Mercedes; Mirand#243;, Joan; Nelson, Paul; Arp, Jean; Leger, Fernand; Callery, Mary; Gabo, Naum; Krasner, Lee; Hofmann, Hans; Carles, Arthur B.; Bergdorf Goodman, New York
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Objects weathervane[;] Shooting Gallery[;] Welt kugel[;] oilte warge fin N.W. Ayer and son[;] Radio Tube[;] Machine Hudson Ave. Generating Station Consolidated Edison[;] ashtray with cigarette hand[;] Schere Glaskrigel[;] bluthen[;] firework[;] Koraller[;] Feuer[;] Wellen in Tray[;] Seil fin montage American Wasp and Nest[;] Driftwood[;] Nachtanfuralum von Schiff heiegt[;] American Flag[;] Film strenfen[;] Schere glas kugel[;] Ashtray with smoke[;] Bermuda Bride's Magazine[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Bride's California Sept. 41[;] Sante Fe Ceremonial Mount[;] Alexander Nehru (Matter)[;]"., b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 132, Folder 1)
    Hofmann, Hans; Carles, Arthur B.;; Rio (Brazil); Gaspe (Quebec); Provincetown (Mass.)
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Ski in California[;] Canada winter lourentions[;]".ND, b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 132, Folder 2)
    Eames, Charles; Ain, Gregory; Eames, Lucia; De Chirico, Giorgio;; Pestalozzi Foundation of America;; San Francisco Bridge
  - Transcribed from Matter's handwritten notes: "Harper's Bazaar[;] Kinde le stoffe[;] Harper's Bazaar 1.7. Avenue 2. Dresses[;] 1 film strenfen, Harper's eye exercise Feb. 43[;] Canada Harpers[;] Calder[;]".ND, b/w 2 1/4" negative strips (Box 132, Folder 3)
    Consolidated Edison Company of New York, inc.
- Series 8: Media, 33.5 linear ft.
  This series includes 16mm film (black and white, and a small amount of color footage), 35mm film (a small amount of footage, and separate audio track recorded on 35mm film stock), audio reels (seven inch magnetic reels), sound disc (records), video (helical scan, one VHS) and audio cassettes. Due to format, condition and viewing equipment, the 16mm film, 35mm film, helical scan video are currently non-viewable. The subjects of the media series are predominately East Indian Dance, Harlem black dance, and Alexander Calder (Works of Calder film). Series includes footage of Matter's film project on Coney Island. For Matter's film work on R. Buckminster Fuller see the R. Buckminster Fuller Papers, ca. 1920-1983. Collection number: Special Collections M1090.
  - Subseries 8.01: 16mm
    - Studio Associates original reel #75923., 2 film reels (212 ft.): 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 337)
      Church negative, roll 28A
    - Studio Associates "Revere" #73946R2.1952 Aug. 22, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 339)
      Includes note stating "Jimmy Studio Hotlip Spear Orchestra church on 145th street"
    - Labeled original Hindu music.1955 May 25, 1 film reel: 16mm: color: no audio. (Othertype 340)
    - Labele original Hindu music #34488.1955 May 25, 2 film reels: 16mm: color: no audio. (Othertype 341)
      Original Kodak reels 1 and 2.
    - Eastern Indian Dance; "Kupura" part 1 #142; "8" part 2 #139.ND, 2 film reels: 16mm: color: no audio. (Othertype 342)
    - "Works of Calder" with edits.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: color: no audio. (Othertype 343)
    - "Reine Dorian Dance reel #24005; Charleston Pix Net; Reel nine".1957 Mar. 21, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 344)
      Music tracks include "Lindy", "Pearls", "Cakewalk", "St. James", "Papade Duet (Clayton)", "Freeze-melt", "Frankie and Johhny", "Charleston", "Change of Key Boogie".
    - Studio Associates; Milliken Studios.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 345)
      Man with guitar dressed in white. 2nd half of reel: piano player, trumpet player, sax player, drummer, clarinet. Female vocalist followed by male vocalists. Man at podium (church). African-American.
    - Related to "Works of Calder" finished with credits.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: color: audio. (Othertype 346)
    - Fragments of "Works of Calder".ND, 12 film reels: 16mm: color: no audio. (Othertype 347)
      Fla - citrus #54-25-1X, Amoco ovalspot 4X
    - African dance "Centro".ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: color: no audio. (Othertype 348)
    - Studio Associates; "God Created Woman" #706014; Reel 1 and 2; Order 70141 dated Sep,18.1952 May 7, 10 film reels: 16mm: b/w: some audio. (Othertype 349)
      Some reels have audio. Includes film leader.
    - Studio #75922 Blank; "Gaspe Color"; Leader.ND, 4 film reels: 16mm: no audio. (Othertype 350)
    - Studio Associates; Reel #73946; African-American men singing into microphone.ND, 4 film reels: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 351)
      Three men are in white tops, two men are in black.
    - "Do not project/splice"; "Works of Calder" with audio;ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: audio. (Othertype 352)
      Narration and production by Burgess Meredith. "Fin de Dixieme et Dernieve Partie" at end. Edit finished.
    - Studio Associates; African dance.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: some audio. (Othertype 353)
      Several subjects includes "Operating poem", "Negro dance", "African tribe"
    - Relates to "The Drifter".ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: color: no audio. (Othertype 354)
    - "Gaspe Color"; Movielab Film Labs; "Guitarist" on reel.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: no audio. (Othertype 355)
      Seagulls on film
    - "Duet New"; "Papa Dee" No; 2; on Kodak reel.ND, 5 film reels: 16mm: some have audio. (Othertype 358)
      close up work pic, "PGD-Duet Tails", Dance (two men with tophats and cane) no audio.
    - Alexander Calder; "Works of Calder".ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: color: no audio:incomplete: several strips of film. (Othertype 359)
    - Alex Matter; Early film involving couple; Not "The Drifter".ND, 4 film reels: 16mm: no audio. b/w. (Othertype 364)
    - Dorian Parts; "Papa da do"; R Twelve; "Live-Die"; Scene on tail; Reine-Dorian.ND, 11 film reels: 16mm: b/w. (Othertype 367)
      Two reels labeled P12-24005 and AC0857-0002
    - Black dance; church.ND, 2 film reels: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 369)
      Reel 1 and 2 #7796
    - James Berry Dance.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: audio only. (Othertype 370)
    - Related to "The Drifter" and 1' length strip of color film "The Drifter".ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio: 1' length strip in color. (Othertype 371)
    - James Berry Dance; "Live-Die".ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 373)
    - Alexander Calder; multiple reels (spools); discards original.ND, 15 film reels: 16mm: color. (Othertype 376)
    - Several reels (spools); Dorian parts; Dance; Segovia has no audio.ND, 16 film reels: 16mm: audio only except Segovia that has no audio. (Othertype 378)
    - Various subjects; buildings; forest.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 379)
    - Black dance.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 380)
    - Coney Island; Black dance; "Charleston"; Walking Charlie; Steeplechase Mirrors with Kids; Swing; Kids on Whip; Kids on Rocket Thriller; Human pool table; Princess Doraldina's hand.ND, 5 film reels: 16mm: color and b/w. (Othertype 382)
    - Eastern Indian Dance; KupuraND, 1 film reel: 16mm: color: no audio. (Othertype 384)
    - Very short reels; Titles include Rolloplane -Pay-CU's with Girls; Mesh - on W;W;; Light Clusters on Steeplechase Carousel; Spitfire - Dusk; Boardwalk Carousel; Andrea and Pundy; Horses; Lights on Carousel (Parachutes BG); Fluorescent Lights on Carousel; Steeplechase Carousel; Bell and Musical Instruments; Shooting Galleries; Hurricane Frome - W;W; Day; Hi-Ball; W;W; at Night; Lights in Carousel Mirrors; Fluorescent Lights on Carousel; Boomerang Lights; Sun Flashes.ND, 15 film reels: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 385)
    - Misc; 16mm strips.ND, 6 film reels: 16mm: b/w: color: some with audio. (Othertype 386)
    - Blackleader.ND, 2 film reels: 16mm: no audio. (Othertype 387)
    - Take 1; Duet; Dance.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 388)
    - Rene Dorian "Live-Die" Dance.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 389)
    - John Oliver's Quartette and his famous Recording Orchestra.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: audio. (Othertype 390)
    - "Herbie's Derby".ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: audio. (Othertype 391)
    - Calder family early 1938.1938, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 392)
    - Dance film; "Charleston - Calypso; Applesack - Big Apple; Al's Blues Rent Party". ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w. (Othertype 393)
      Reel 2 A3133
    - Coney Island.ND, 1 film reel: 16mm: color: audio. Trims and outs on reel (Othertype 394)
    - African Dance.ND, 2 film reels: 16mm: audio. (Othertype 395)
    - Eastern Indian Dance; Kupura.ND, 7 film reels: 16mm: color: no audio. (Othertype 398)
    - Kupura Eastern Indian Dance; "Memories of an old timer"., 36105115666799; 4 film reels: 16mm: b/w and color: no audio. (Othertype 403)
    - Rene Dorian Dance reel., 36105115666807; 1 film reel: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 404)
    - "Live-Die"; Black dance., 36105115666815; 1 film reel: 1 film strip: 16mm: b/w: no audio. (Othertype 405)
      Includes titles/labels from unidentified film cannisters and reels.
    - Alexander Calder strips sandwiched between glass plates.ND, Various 16mm strips in envelopes or between paper. (Othertype 415)
  - Subseries 8.02: 35mm
    - Music track for jazz dance films., 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 336)
    - Music tracks for jazz dance films.1957 Jul. 1, 1 film reel: 35mm: music audio only. (Othertype 338)
    - Dancing with James Berry.ND, 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 356)
      Includes tracks "Live-Die", "Walk Stick", "New Music", "Track D", "Poses".
    - Title "Interlude Music"; Dancing with James Berry.ND, 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 357)
      Track 13.
    - "Music Outs"; "Jazz"; "W;B; Cuts"; "Dance"; "Charleston"; "Papa da do" [Film cannister 1 of 2].ND, 2 film reels: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 360)
    - "Music Outs"; "Jazz"; "W;B; Cuts"; "Dance"; "Poses"; "Charleston"; [Film cannister 2 of 2];ND, 4 film reels: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 361)
    - "Pearls"; Take 3.ND, 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 362)
    - "New Poses" (Dance); "Guns of August"; film leader.ND, 4 film reels: 35mm: no audio. (Othertype 363)
    - "Papa da do"; Buck Clayton.ND, 4 film reels: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 365)
    - "Cakewalk" #1 trios music; Take 3.1956 May 23, 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 366)
    - "Walk"; Bert"; "Stick and Williams".ND, 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 368)
    - Buck Clayton; Lindy dance.ND, 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 372)
    - "I'm in Dove".ND, 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 374)
    - Dizzy Lollo.ND, 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 375)
    - Track E; "Live-Die"; Answer-voice; Rock Roll voices; Dancing with James Berry.ND, 1 film reel: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 377)
    - James Berry dance music.ND, 1 film reel: 35mm: b/w: audio only. (Othertype 381)
    - "Bongo; Bongo; Bongo-1";"Bongo; Bongo; Bongo-2";"Bongo; Bongo; Bongo-2B";"Near You"; "Nut Rocker 2";"The Moon and the Sea" ND, 8 film reels: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 396)
    - "Bongo Rock-2"; More-Waltz"; "Nutcracker Suite"; "Boogie Woogie"; "Models in Blue".ND, 5 film reels: 35mm: audio only. (Othertype 397)
  - Subseries 8.03: Audio Reels
    - Paul Robeson; L-301; Reel 1.ND, 1 magnetic tape: 7 in. (Othertype 301)
    - Paul Robeson; L-301; Reel 2.ND, 1 magnetic tape: 7 in. (Othertype 301)
    - Louis Finkelstein; McDougal Alley.1960 May 5, 1 magnetic tape: 7 in. (Othertype 301)
    - Mercedes Matter on Giacometti.1974 April 29, 1 magnetic tape: 7 in. (Othertype 301)
      Relates to Giacometti
    - Unidentified audio recording.ND, 1 magnetic tape: 7 in. (Othertype 301)
  - Subseries 8.04: Sound Disc
    - Songbirds of America with commentary by A; A; Allen; tracks include Bluebird; Brown Thrasher; Chicadee; Carolina Wren; Re-eyed Vireo; Warbling Vireo; Yellow Warbler; Robin; Goldfinch; Catbird; Red-winged Blackbird; Rose-breasted Grosbeak; Bobolink; Mockingbird; Meadowlark; Indigo Bunting; Baltimore Oriole; Wood Thrush; House Wren; Song Sparrow; Fox Sparrow; White-throated Sparrow; Pewee; Cardinal.ND, 1 sound disc: analog: 33 1/3 rpm: 12 in. (Othertype 301)
      Original Source. Usage unknown. Recorded in the wild for Albert R. Brand Bird Song Foundation. Produced by P. P. Kellogg and A. A. Allen. Laboratory of Ornithology, Dept. of Conservation, Cornell University. 24 tracks. 12 tracks per side.
    - A Little Girl Grew Up a Little Last Night.ND, 1 sound disc: analog: 45 rpm: 7 in. (Othertype 301)
      Original Source. Usage unknown. Produced by Associated Recording Studios. Single track on one side only.
    - Live Till I Die; Several music sheets are included with the sound disc which are unrelated to the title.ND, 1 sound disc: analog: 10 in. (Othertype 301)
      Produced by Nola Recording Studios. Single track on one side only.Relates to Matter's Dance films.
  - Subseries 8.05: Video
    - Julian Levy reel #1 on surrealism with showing of film by J. Levy.1972 Mar. 22, Sony video 5" reel tape type V-30H. Helical scan. (Othertype 301)
    - Julian Levy reel #2 on surrealism with showing of film by J. Levy.1972 Mar. 22, Sony video 5" reel tape type V-30H. Helical scan. (Othertype 301)
    - Herbert Matter out takes of Calder Film.ND, 1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in.: 120 min: no audio. (Othertype 301)
  - Subseries 8.06: Audio Cassettes
    - Audio cassette tape "for Mercedes".1974 Dec. 6, 120 minute audio cassette tape. 60 minutes per side running time (Othertype 301)
    - Audio cassette tape labeled "A;G; 78 lecture"; other side is labeled "Giacometti 78 lecture"., 60 minute sound cassette running time (Othertype 301)
    - Audio cassette tape labeled "Giacometti" #1 and #2., 120 minute sound cassette running time (Othertype 301)
    - Audio cassette tape labeled "Giacometti" #3., 120 minute sound cassette running time (Othertype 301)
    - Audio cassette tape labeled "AG 78 88"; Giacometti., 120 minute sound cassette running time (Othertype 301)
    - Audio cassette tape labeled "1B" and other side "2B"; unidentified., 60 minute sound cassette running time (Othertype 301)
- Series 9: Photographs Gifted from the Matter Family, 1.5 linear ft.
  This series contains 300 vintage black and white photographic prints by Herbert Matter. These prints were selected from the Matter Family's personal collection to broadly represent Herbert Matter photographic career, his commercial and non-commercial work. The prints demonstrate Matter's aesthetic and the various photographic and darkroom techniques he employed. Includes examples of infra-red photography, solarization, electrographic photography, photogram, and studio prints. The prints are organized by subject matter in the following categories: Abstracts; Biographical; Alexander Calder; Fashion; Alberto Giacometti; Knoll Associates; Land and Seascapes; Mercedes Matter; Museums; Personal Photography; Portraits; Commercial.
  - Subseries 9.01: Abstracts
    - "Umbrella; "For a rainy day I, New York 1978"; [Folder 1]."1978 ca., 36105115667201; 16"x20": Marked on back in pencil "2/10 photography by Herbert Matter" with diagram showing print arrangement of images in series. (Othertype 407, Folder 1)
    - Rock formation with lines; [Folder 1].1979 ca., 36105115667219; 16"x20": Marked on front in black pen "1/50 Herbert Matter": Written on back in black ink "Photograph by Herbert Matter" and 'Sunshine Island: Maine VI 1979" (Othertype 407, Folder 2)
    - Rock formation; extreme close up with single curved line; [Folder 1].1979 ca., 36105115667227; 16"x20": Marked on front in black pen "2/50 Herbert Matter": Written on back in black ink "Photograph by Herbert Matter" and 'Sunshine Island: Maine IV 1979" (Othertype 407, Folder 3)
    - Two limes with cloth; [Folder 1].1979 ca., 36105115667235; 16"x20": Marked on back in blue ink "Photograph by Herbert Matter 19 Macdougal Alley New York N.Y. 10011" and "'Composition with Two Limes' 1979". Written on back in pencil is "2" and is circled. (Othertype 407, Folder 4)
    - Pavement with empty cans; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667243; 16"x20" (Othertype 407, Folder 5)
    - Geometric forms; including test tube with 3D effect for Wyandotte Chemicals Corporation; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667250; 16"x20": Stamped on back "Studio Associates" (Othertype 407, Folder 6)
    - Pebble with tree bark on black background; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667268; 16"x20" (Othertype 407, Folder 7)
    - "Driftwood floating on black background; [Folder 1]; "Composition, 1943".", 36105115667276; 16"x20" (Othertype 407, Folder 8)
    - "Frozen water; icicles on tree; "Icicles, New York 1978"; [Folder 1]."1978 ca., 36105115667284; 16"x20" (Othertype 407, Folder 9)
    - Random objects on pavement; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667292; 16"x20": written on back in pencil is an "X". (Othertype 407, Folder 10)
    - Solarized random objects on pavement; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667300; 16"x20": written on back in pencil is an "X". (Othertype 407, Folder 11)